

Hamburg, Germany

□ +49 15203762106 | ■ maksimov.dmitry.m@gmail.com | □ Maksimov-Dmitry | 🛅 Maksimov-Dmitry | 🐚 maksimov.dmitry.m

### Summary.

4+ years of diverse data/software engineering experience with specialties in pipelines integration, architecture design using AWS, database maintenance and deployment.

4+ years of diverse machine learning and AI engineering with a focus on model management, deployment and researching.

2+ years of diverse data science experience with specialties in market research, data visualization, causal modelling, market optimization and model lifecycle.

In addition, while studying at the university and courses(e.g. MADE from VK), learned many skills like: Reinforcement Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Pytorch, Transformers, Huggingface, PyTorch Lightning, Optimization, Spark, Hadoop, Scala, Recommender Systems, algorithms, A/B testing and data structures.

# Skills\_

AWS, Azure, Kubernetes, Docker, GitHub, Retool, Linux, Bash, REST API, Google Cloud, CI/CD, MLflow, Airflow, Vertex AI

RAG, LLM, Statistical Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Probability Theory, XGBoost, PyTorch, scikit-learn, ETL, Vertica, Search **ML & Data Science** 

Engine Optimization, PostgreSQL, Market Research, Parsing, Streamlit, SageMaker

**Programming** Python, SQL, SAS base Languages Russian, English, German

# Work Experience

neuland.ai Cologne, Germany

Al Developer May. 2024 - Present

- Led the development of multiple client projects generating a total revenue €200K, as well as various internal initiatives
- Created RAG chatbot applications within Azure for more than 5 customers
- Established best practices for Azure development and deployment for a team of more than 10 developers
- Developed CI/CD pipelines for automatic deployment ant testing of customer projects and internal ones
- Participated in colloquiums focused on RAG systems
- Established and embedded software development best practices into the company's workflows, benefiting a team of over 10 developers
- Stack: Azure, RAG, Azure Kubernetes Service, LLM, Chatbots, Cloud Applications, FastAPI

T.C.R. International

SENIOR DATA & SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2021 - Jan. 2024

Apr. 2022 - Oct. 2023

- Led the design and maintenance of financial system procedures, engaging in 90% of process advancements, leading to a 30% reduction in day end closing time
- Simplified airflow dags and configuration which allowed reducing the cost of the astronomer by 70%
- Analyzed AWS infrastructure costs to identify inefficiencies and improved cost optimization strategies, resulting in a 20% decreasing in monthly cloud expenses
- Implemented AWS Lambda functions for data ingestion and processing, reducing processing time by 50%
- · Launched a Deep Learning trading algorithm with predictive analytics capabilities, leading to a 100% improvement in accuracy of market movement forecasts
- · Directed the development and establishment of structured protocols for maintaining and updating a comprehensive internal symbology database housing over 30,000 symbols
- · Led the development and implementation of a high-reliability process in AWS, responsible for managing key company operations, including a process overseeing over \$2 billion in financial transactions
- · Integrated IaC practices to standardize and automate infrastructure deployment, creating fully reproducible scripts for scalable and consistent infrastructure management
- · Mentored two team members simultaneously by creating tasks aligned with business and technical requirements, conducting code reviews, and leading sessions on development best practices
- Stack: Python, AWS, Airflow, PostgreSQL, Docker, CI/CD, PyTorch, XGBoost, Terraform

**GFK** Nuremberg, Germany

- Created a proprietary tool to evaluate market segmentations, analyzing purchase trends and consumer behavior
- · Conducted in depth competitor analysis to understand cannibalization effects on market share
- Maintained the CI/CD pipeline

DATA SCIENTIST & MLOPS

- Engineered the migration strategy for a Deep Learning model onto Vertex AI on Google Cloud, achieving a 50% decrease in model deployment time and increasing scalability by 3x
- Stack: Python, Google Cloud Platform, Streamlit, PostgreSQL, Vertex AI, CI/CD

**SDVOR** Moscow, Russia

DATA SCIENTIST Apr 2020 - Jan 2022

- Created an attribution model in advertising for a site; optimized ad spend allocation resulting in a 5% reduction in advertising costs
- Designed and deployed ETL workflows to parse competitor site data, enabling automated extraction and loading of 5K+ records daily, leading to a 25% increase in data accuracy and efficiency
- Developed and implemented a pricing optimization system leveraging SAS, Python, and SQL to analyze market trends and consumer behavior, leading to a 10% profit increase on specific products
- Engineered a sophisticated computer vision system that compared planograms with realograms through image analysis in retail stores, having the effect of 35% reduction in out of stock items
- Developed a Telegram bot server for automating 10+ daily operational tasks, resulting in a 30% reduction in manual errors
- Orchestrated a machine learning initiative that analyzed historical data to pinpoint bottlenecks in the distribution network; decreased shipping
- Stack: Python, SAS, Vertica, PostgreSQL, Telegram API

### **Education**

M.S. IN DATA SCIENCE

### FAU(Friedrich-Alexander-Universität Erlangen-Nürnberg)

Erlangen-Nürnberg, Germany

Developed Personalized Anomaly Detection Model based on continuous-time LSTM and Bayesian Decision Theory.

- Developing a Query-Answering System for Technical Documentation Using Domain-Optimized Language Models.
- Stack: Pytorch, Transformers, Hydra, SageMaker, AWS, Reinforcement Learning, NLP, RAG, AimStack/MLFlow

### BMSTU(Bauman Moscow State Technical University)

Moscow, Russia

Oct. 2021 - May 2024

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep. 2020 - Jun. 2021

#### BMSTU(Bauman Moscow State Technical University)

Moscow, Russia

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep. 2016 - Jun. 2020

# Extracurricular Activity \_\_\_\_\_

MADE at VK Moscow, Russia

Sep. 2022 - Jun. 2023 STUDENT

- Gained expertise in different areas of ML (e.g. NLP, DL, Computer Vision, MLOps, basic ML, Python, ML in BigData, etc)
- Core member in a project to create a recommendation system for articles' authors and User Request-Based Fake Web Document Text Generation system

ML at Mail.ru Group Moscow, Russia

· Gained knowledge in basic ML

Sep. 2020 - Jan. 2021

### **Certificates**

STUDENT

Dec. 2023 GPT Week, Yandex, School of data analysis

Aug. 2023 AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, AWS

Jun. 2023 MADE Big Data Academy. Machine Learning Engineer, VK

405-67419

Oct. 2022 Completion of the Deep Learning Exercise, FAU

Mar. 2020 Labeled data learning, Coursera

Mar. 2020 Math and Python for data analysis, Coursera

Oct. 2019 C/C++, Mail.ru Group

## **Honors & Awards**

### INTERNATIONAL AWARDS

Mar. 2024 1st Place, GEN AI Hackathon(Hotels search engine with advanced RAG)

San Francisco, USA

Jan. 2023 8th Place, Tensor Tournament

Erlangen, Germany Erlangen, Germany

Oct. 2022 2nd Place, Classification of Solar Cell Defects

#### **DOMESTIC AWARDS**

Oct. 2021 1st Place, SDVOR Hacking Competition

Tyumen, Russia